LAURA WALTERS

Erdington, West Midlands, B23 5RL
Phone: 07572272850| Email: lauraewalters1098@gmail.com
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/laura-walters-099137215/ |
GitHub: https://github.com/laurawalters1 | Portfolio:
https://laurawalters1.github.io/laura-walters-portfolio/

SUMMARY

A great team player, fast learner, and innovative thinker beginning a career in software development. Strong knowledge of programming fundamentals, and experience and proficiency in the application of this knowledge to the learning of new technologies. Having completed a Full-stack Coding Bootcamp Certificate with the University of Birmingham, alongside a full-time Level 3 Software Development Technician Apprenticeship with Baltic apprenticeships, applying skills to a broad range of languages, frameworks and technologies.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages:

Proficient in: JavaScript, Express, Sequelize, Handlebars, MongoDB, Mongoose,

React, GraphQL

Experience with: PHP, Laravel

Currently learning: C#, dotnet, Angular

Tools:

Frequently used: npm, Composer, GitHub, Heroku, AWS JawsDB, Azure Data Factory,

Azure DevOps

Encountered: AWS S3 Bucket, MongoDB Atlas, PowerBI, Azure App Service

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant | December 2022 - Present | EdX

In my current evening role I work as a teaching assistant on a Frontend Web Development bootcamp. For this role I am tasked with assisting students with coding activities in breakout rooms, including running through the solutions, taking questions and making sure misunderstandings are addressed.

Graduate Software Developer | Sept 2022 - Present | Jumar

In my current role I am working in agile development, creating an internal dashboard to be used for viewing data relating to the recruitment side of the business. To do this I am using C# to query data from an external api, an Azure Data factory to flatten the JSON data that is returned from the api call so that it can be stored in table format in an Azure SQL database. I am finally using PowerBI to formulate the visuals for this data.

Apprentice Web Developer | Dec 2021 – Aug 2022 | Central Learning Partnership Trust

Wolverhampton, West Midlands

In this role, I worked alongside two other developers to build projects required by the trust to support school and trust operations, using PHP and Laravel. I contributed to a long-term project that aimed to enable an efficient point of reference for the status of staff documents across the trust. In this project I had input on both front-end and back-end code, and frequently used my own initiative and innovation to suggest new ideas for features that could be included in the project to improve user-experience, and thus the quality of the overall project, and could see that my input was valued and often my ideas were utilised, or I was provided with constructive feedback which I can use to improve my ideas in the future.

PROJECTS

Macro Meals

Github repository: https://github.com/laurawalters1/meal-planner-project-1 Deployed app: https://laurawalters1.github.io/meal-planner-project-1/

Summary:

Macro Meals is a meal planning app which allows a user to input their height, weight, age, daily activity, and goals, and receive a custom calorie recommendation, as well as a suggested macronutrient ratio, and a full weeks-worth of recipe ideas. Macro Meals also enables a user to save their entered values, and save meals that they like the look of to their own personal CookBook.

My Role:

Teamed up with two other developers, we each took ownership of the project and all took the responsibility of managing the project as a whole, and contributing ideas for additional features. In addition to this, I took on the responsibility of the persistence of user data, through the use of local storage, which is demonstrated in the storage of user metrics, and the storage of recipes in the CookBook.

Tools used: Github, GitHub projects, Fitness Calculator api, Edamam Recipe api **Languages used:** JavaScript

Travelly

Deployed app: https://gentle-lowlands-70428.herokuapp.com/ Github repository: https://github.com/laurawalters1/travelly-app

Summary:

Travelly is a social media and advertising platform for users who are interested in gap-year style trips, where they can travel and meet new people and create experiences. Travelly aims to gamify the travel experience, by giving users the opportunity to earn unique badges to display on their profile, based on which trips they have been on and which countries each trip visits. Travelly also provides a live chat to users that are booked on the same trip, so that they have a chance to socialise and get to know each other before travelling.

My Role:

Taking inspiration from my own previous project, I took on a leadership role in the

implementation of this app, finding a way to integrate the desire of my teammates to have some sort of user-achievement system into the travel app concept. Throughout the project, I played a large role in the planning and execution of the structure and interaction of the backend functionality. After a short period of detailed planning, I was able to foresee potential issues, and thus provide a data structure which would minimise these issues, and due to this, the creation of the backend of this project ran relatively smoothly when taking into account its complexity.

Tools used: Github, GitHub projects, Draw IO, AWS S3 bucket, Socket IO, Chakra UI, React, GraphQL, MongoDB Atlas and Mongoose

Languages used: JavaScript

EDUCATION

Boot Camp Certificate University of Birmingham

Birmingham, West Midlands

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, and ReactJS. In addition to the development of the aforementioned technical skills, I have also gained invaluable skills in collaborative development and project management, completing three group projects, during which my team and I would manage the full software development lifecycle, from feasibility and planning, to deployment and maintenance. Using GitHub projects and KanBan to manage this process, I have developed confidence with this method of collaboration and can integrate well into a team.

BSc - Sport and Exercise Science, University of Birmingham - 2020

In 2020 I graduated with a 2:1 Bsc in Sport and Exercise Science from the University of Birmingham. Throughout this 3 year programme, I developed valuable skills in time-management, discipline and presentation of work.

School

A-level 2016

71.70101 =0.70	
Subject	Grad e
Psycholog y	Α
Sociolog y	Α
English	В

GCSE (2014)

Subject	Grad
	е

English Language	Α
English literature	В
Maths	В
Biology	C
Physics	С
Chemistry	В
Psychology	Α
Art	O
Geography	В
Food technology	В
Citizenship studies	С